Alexander W. Tickle

2107 Stackhouse Drive, Yardley, PA 19067 | (267) 346-1030 | alexander.tickle@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexander-tickle | Portfolio: https://alextickle.github.io

SUMMARY

Full stack web developer with strong analytical skills and broad competence across the full life cycle of modern web development, from gathering requirements from stakeholders to testing and deployment. Particular expertise in Java, Spring Boot, and React.

SKILLS

Languages – JavaScript, Java, SQL, CSS, HTML

Frameworks/Libraries – React, Spring Boot, Express, Spring Data JPA, JUnit, Redux, Apollo, WebdriverIO, Jest, Cypress **Tools** - Postman, Maven, GraphQL, Argo CD, Gatling, Docker, Artifactory, Jenkins, Splunk, Spinnaker, AWS, Kubernetes

WORK EXPERIENCE

Intuit | San Diego, CA

Senior Software Engineer

October 2017 – November 2019

- Replaced Developer Portal's existing SQL-based search with Elasticsearch to improve performance and allow for more complex query logic
- Built scheduled tasks and messaging queues to sync MySQL data with newly created Elasticsearch indices
- Investigated customer satisfaction with Developer Portal's Elasticsearch search feature by conducting detailed "follow me home" interviews with end users and presented findings and recommendations to product management
- Implemented search improvements using ElasticSearch's function score API and measured impact with Delighted net promoter score
- Wrote bash scripts to efficiently update and query Elasticsearch indices from my desktop with awscurl
- Migrated five Spring Boot microservices from private data center to AWS, which involved extensive cooperation with database administrators, operations, and security teams
- Led weekly application deployments with Kubernetes and ArgoCD during difficult transition where applications were only partially migrated to AWS and data needed to be replicated between private data center MySql databases and AWS Aurora data stores
- Conducted numerous knowledge sharing sessions and authored wikis to teach team members about new deployment processes required by migration to AWS
- Collaborated with security team to conduct extensive security review of new AWS microservice architecture and produce detailed diagrams of application components
- Upgraded ksonnet Kubernetes configuration to kustomize yaml-based configuration
- Wrote and optimized multi-table SQL queries to measure organization-level adoption of leadership initiatives
- Built React components to display adoption data in custom sortable table
- Administered legacy Angular/Spring Java application that tracks employee achievements and upgraded it to Spring Boot 2
- Granted granular resource access to employee users to create and award their own custom "badges" to recognize various achievements at Intuit
- Took over responsibility for development and maintenance of performance tests written in Scala and executed with Gatling after performance engineers left the company
- Wrote and maintained Jenkinsfiles for five Spring Boot microservices to orchestrate build, testing, and deployment from Jenkins server
- Built React component to allow users to change their application's API gateway configuration in real time
- Built and optimized SQL-based typeahead search for Node application
- Developed browser automation test suite for React components using WebdriverIO and integrated test execution into automated build process
- Added virus scanning orchestration logic to document upload widgets used within TurboTax's W2 upload flow
- Conducted code reviews on all PRs submitted to repositories under my jurisdiction
- Participated in monthly support rotation as frontline support engineer where I worked directly with end customers to debug, triage, escalate, and resolve issues using Splunk logs
- Technologies: Java, Javascript, Spring Boot, Spring Data, React, MySQL, Kubernetes, Docker, ArgoCD, Jenkins, Postman, Maven, Gradle, Gatling, Artifactory, Jenkins, Splunk, Spinnaker, AWS, Aurora, Elasticsearch, Kibana, Jest, Cypress, JUnit, Github

MJD Interactive | San Diego, CA

Web Development Intern

- Built Node/Express application with Postgres SQL database

- Wrote GraphQL schema to enable use of custom queries from /graphql endpoint
- Converted query results into Javascript objects using Sequelize ORM

June 2017 – September 2017

- Integrated GraphQL data into React frontend using Apollo
- Built front end React components to display consumer product information
- Worked with QA to identify and fix bugs
- Provided browser support for Chrome, Firefox, Safari, IE 10, Microsoft Edge
- Participated in daily scrum with development team and client representative
- Technologies: Javascript, Node, Express, Reach, GraphQL, Apollo, Redux, Jest, BitBucket, Git, Pivotal Tracker, Sequelize, Ansible

CETRA Language Solutions | San Diego, CA

April 2016 – March 2017

Project Manager

- Managed translation projects from client handoff to final delivery for market research firms

Local Concept, Inc | San Diego, CA

June 2015 – April 2016

Project Coordinator

- Prepared xml files for localization and organized translators for HP, our largest client

Max Planck Institute for Evolutionary Anthropology (MPI-EVA) | Leipzig, Germany *Field Site Manager*

August 2013 – December 2014

- Managed temporary field site for chimpanzee research in GEPRENAF zone of northern Côte d'Ivoire as part of MPI-EVA's Pan African Program (comparative study of chimpanzees at 30+ field sites across Africa)
- Responsible for all data collection, logistics, team management, and accounting for entire 15-month study
- Extensive use of handheld GPS, GIS software, and Excel
- Coauthored "Chimpanzee accumulative stone throwing" (manuscript published in Scientific Reports, https://www.nature.com/articles/srep22219)

EDUCATION

LEARN Academy | San Diego, CA

March 2017 – June 2017

JavaScript full stack JavaScript web development boot camp – Node, Express, React, PostgreSQL

UC San Diego Extension | San Diego, CA

July 2016 – September 2017

Java Programming Certificate Program

University of Pennsylvania | Philadelphia, PA

2009 -2013

Bachelor of Arts in Anthropology